inkling.com 2016-03-10

# Privacy - Inkling

Inkling Systems, Inc. (“Inkling” or “we” or “us”) recognizes that your privacy is very important and takes it seriously. This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) describes Inkling’s policies and procedures on the collection, use and disclosure of your personally identifiable information (“Personal Information”) when you use the Inkling website and domain name, any other linked pages, features, content, mobile applications, and any other services we offer from time to time in connection with any of the above (collectively, the “Service”). The Inkling Terms of Use, including their paragraphs limiting damages and providing for individual arbitration of disputes, apply to and are incorporated by reference into this Policy. This Policy does not apply to information we collect by other means (including offline) or from other sources.

#### Information Collected by Inkling

Inkling uses the Personal Information and other information we collect to, among other things, analyze how the Service is used, diagnose service or technical problems, maintain security, personalize content, remember information to help you efficiently access your account, monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, traffic, and demographic patterns, and track user content and users as necessary to improve the Service and comply with applicable laws.

You can choose not to provide us with any or all of the information we specify or request, but then you may not be able to register with us or to take advantage of some or all of our features.

The Inkling Service is available to business and enterprise customers (and their users, collectively, the “business users”). In order to provide the Service, Inkling collects information from its business users that may include personal information of business users. We also collect certain information directly from business users’ employees and other users who access the Service. Certain Inkling services and features also available to consumers (the “consumer users”). Unless otherwise noted, references to users or end users include both consumer users and business users.

**_Information We Collect Directly._** When a user registers for an account with us, accesses our Service, or updates their profile with us, we collect certain information directly from that user, including name and email address, as well as other information added to a user’s profile.

We may also receive certain additional user information from our business users. For example, our business users may provide us with the names and email addresses of their employees or other agents who are authorized to access the Service, as well as other information about such employees or agents.

Your name and other information you choose to add to your profile may be available to other users of the Service. Users may also be able to follow other users; if a user chooses to follow you, the user will be able to see the information, such as notes and certain profile information, that you have not set to private. Consumer users may login to Inkling using their social networking site (“SNS”) account credentials. If you use your Facebook®, Twitter®, or other SNS credentials to sign in to Inkling, we will collect and store your SNS user ID. We may also collect information you supply to us regarding your personal preferences and interests. If you use your SNS account credentials to access the Service, you understand that some content and/or information in your SNS account (“Third Party Account Information”) may be transmitted into your account with us if you authorize such transmissions, and that Third Party Account Information transmitted to our Service is covered by this Policy. You also provide us information by submitting user-generated content to the Service (“User-generated Content”), including your notes and highlights, and collaborate with other users.

_Consumer Users._  Your User-generated Content, and metadata about it (such as when you submitted the User-generated Content), may be viewable by other Inkling users, along with your first name and the first initial of your last name (unless the Service permits you to post anonymously). You may generally control whether your User-generated Content is private or public either at the time you submit such information or when setting the preferences for your account.

_Business Users._  Business users can collaborate with other business users, their subcontractors and other collaborators within the same organizations, as part of a project or otherwise. In such cases, the content you post is shared with these other users unless you set it to private; your name and email address is also viewable by other users within your organization.

**_Invite A Friend._** Consumer users may invite other users and share or gift content to other consumer users. If you choose to follow a friend using the Service, invite a friend to use the Service or gift Inkling content to a friend, we will ask you for that person’s email address. Inkling stores the email addresses you submit to send relevant communications, to register your friend if your invitation or gift is accepted, to track the success of invitation and gifting programs, and to identify your friends on Inkling.

**_Information We Collect Automatically._** We may automatically collect the following information about your use of our Service through cookies, web beacons, and other technologies: your domain name; your browser type and operating system; web pages you view; links you click; your IP address; the length of time you use our Services; the referring URL, or the webpage or other source, that led you to our site; access time; and any device identifier. We may combine this information with other information that we have collected about you, including, where applicable, your user name, name, and other personal information Please see the section “Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms” below for more information.

**_Location Information._** In addition, we may collect different types of information about your location, including general information (e.g., IP address, zip code) and more specific information (e.g., GPS-based functionality on mobile devices used to access the Service), and may use that information to customize the Service with location-based information and features. If you access the Service through a mobile device and you do not want your device to provide us with location-tracking information, you can disable the GPS or other location-tracking functions on your device, provided your device allows you to do this.

#### How We Use Your Personal Information

We use the information that we gather about you for the following sorts of purposes:

  * To provide Service to you, to communicate with you about your use of our Service, to respond to your inquiries, to fulfill your orders, and for other customer service purposes.
  * To tailor the content and information that we may send or display to you, to offer location customization, or to otherwise personalize your experiences while using our Service.
  * For marketing and promotional purposes. For example, we may use your email address, to email you about products or information we think may interest you. We may also use the information that we learn about you to help determine when and how to advertise our services on third party websites, advertising networks and services, or to customize the advertising or experience on our own website and Service.
  * To better understand how users access and use our Service, both on an aggregated and individualized basis, in order to improve our Service, respond to user preferences, and for other research and analytical purposes.
  * As required or otherwise permitted by law.

#### How We Share Your Information

Inkling shares your Personal Information as described below.

  * **_Service Providers._**  In certain situations, we employ other companies and people to perform tasks on our behalf and share your information with them to provide that service. Except as stated in this privacy policy or unless we inform you otherwise, our agents do not have any right to use the Personal Information we share with them beyond what we deem necessary to assist us in performing such tasks.
  * **_Other Users._**  Certain user profile information, including without limitation, a user’s username and the image content that such user has uploaded to our website may be displayed to other users to facilitate user interaction within the Service, to address your request for our services or to otherwise enable features of the Service. Any content you upload to your public user profile, along with any Personal Information or content that you voluntarily disclose online in a manner other users can view (on discussion boards, in messages and chat areas, etc.) is viewable by others.
  * **_Third Party sites and Applications._**  Businesses or third party websites we work with may provide services to you through the Service (either alone or jointly with us). For example, we include the ability for you to automatically transmit information from your Inkling account to an account on a third party website or service, such as Facebook. We do not control the policies and practices of third party websites or businesses, such as Facebook, even if they may be affiliated or partnered with us or the Service, so if you choose to take part in any transaction or service relating to a third party website or business, please review all relevant privacy and other policies of such website or business.
  * **_Affiliates._**  We may disclose the Personal Information we collect from you to our affiliates or subsidiaries; however, if we do so, their use and disclosure of your Personal Information will be subject to this Policy.
  * **_Business Transactions._**  As we develop our business, we may buy or sell assets or business offerings. Customer, email and visitor information is generally one of the transferred business assets in these types of transactions. We may also transfer or assign such information in the course of corporate divestitures, mergers or dissolution.
  * **_Legal Requirements and Protection._**  Inkling may disclose your Personal Information if required to do so by law, court order, subpoena, other legal process, or if we believe that it is reasonably necessary to comply with a law, regulation or legal request; to protect the safety of any person; to address fraud, security or technical issues; or to protect Inkling’s rights or property.
  * **_Aggregate and/or Non-identified Information._**  Inkling may disclose aggregate and/or non-identified information collected through the Service and the use and disclosure of such aggregate and/or de-identified information by Inkling or third parties is not subject to any restrictions under this Policy.

#### Our Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms

We and our third party service providers use cookies and other tracking mechanisms to track information about your use of our Service. We may combine this information with other personal information we collect from you (and our third party service providers may do so on our behalf).

**_Cookies._**  Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser for record-keeping purposes. Some cookies allow us to make it easier for you to navigate our Service, while others are used to enable a faster log-in process, to allow us to track your activities on our Service, or to otherwise enable Service features. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can edit your browser options to block them in the future. The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your computer from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Visitors to our site who disable cookies will be able to browse certain areas of the site, but some features may not function.

**_Clear GIFs, pixel tags and other technologies._**  Clear GIFs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on your computer’s hard drive, clear GIFs are embedded invisibly on web pages. We may use clear GIFs (also known as web beacons, web bugs or pixel tags), in connection with our site to, among other things, track the activities of site visitors, help us manage content and compile statistics about site usage. We or our service providers may also use clear GIFs in HTML emails to our customers to help us track email response rates, identify when our emails are viewed and track whether our emails are forwarded.

**_LSOs._** We or third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features of the Service or to display advertising based upon your tracked activity may use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) using technologies such as HTML5 or Flash to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. To learn about managing Flash LSOs, please click [here](https://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html).

**_Third-party Analytics._**  We use third party analytics tools, such as Google Analytics, to collect, monitor and analyze collected information in order to improve functionality and user-friendliness, and to better tailor the Services to our visitors’ needs. Accordingly, usage data is shared with Google, which has its own [privacy policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) addressing how it uses such information. We encourage you to review this privacy policy to understand how Google uses such information.

#### California Do Not Track Disclosure

**_Currently, our systems do not recognize browser “do-not-track” requests._**  You may, however, disable certain tracking as discussed above (e.g., by disabling cookies). For more information about tracking, please click [here](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/).

#### Interest-Based Advertising

We use third parties such as network advertisers to serve advertisements on our Site and on third-party websites or other media (e.g. social networking platforms). For example, we use LinkedIn, Microsoft AdCenter, and Google Ad Words to serve advertisements on third-party websites. This enables us and these third parties to target advertisements to you for products and services in which you might be interested. Third-party ad network providers, advertisers, sponsors and/or traffic measurement services may use cookies, JavaScript, web beacons (including clear GIFs), LSOs and other tracking technologies to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content to you. These third-party cookies and other technologies are governed by each third party’s specific privacy policy, not this one. We may provide these third-party advertisers with information, including Personal Information, about you.

Users in the United States may opt out of many third-party ad networks. For example, you may go to the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) [Consumer Choice Page](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) for information about opting out of interest-based advertising and choices regarding having information used by [DAA companies](http://www.aboutads.info/participating). You may also go to the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) [Consumer Opt-Out Page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) for information about opting out of interest-based advertising and choices regarding having information used by NAI members.

Users in the European Union may also opt out of many third-party ad networks. For example, you may go to the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance (“EDAA”) [Your Online Choices Page](http://youronlinechoices.eu/) for information about opting out of interest-based advertising and choices regarding having information used by [EDAA members](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/goodpractice).

Opting out from one or more companies listed on the DAA [Consumer Choice Page](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/), the [NAI Consumer Opt-Out Page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) or the EDAA [Your Online Choices Page](http://youronlinechoices.eu/) will opt you out from those companies’ delivery of interest-based content or ads to you, but it does not mean you will no longer receive any advertising through our Site or on other websites. You may continue to receive advertisements, for example, based on the particular website that you are viewing (i.e., contextually based ads). Also, if your browsers are configured to reject cookies when you opt out on the DAA, NAI, or EDAA-related websites, your opt out may not be effective. Additional information is available on the DAA’s website at [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/), the NAI’s website at [www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/), and the EDAA’s website at [www.youronlinechoices.com/goodpractice](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/goodpractice).

#### How We Communicate With You

We may use your email address to send you Service-related notices (including any notices required by law, in lieu of communication by postal mail). We may also use your contact information to send you marketing email messages. If you do not want to receive such messages, you may opt out by following the instructions in the message. If you do not wish to receive email offers and certain Service-related messages, please indicate your preference in your “Privacy Settings” in the Inkling application or on the Inkling website. It may take up to 10 business days for us to process your opt-out request. If you correspond with us by email, we may retain the content of your email messages, your email address and our responses.

#### User Generated Content

We invite you to post content on our Service, including your comments, pictures, and any other information that you would like to be available on our site. If you post content, the information that you post may be available to any other users of our Services. Your posting may become public and we cannot prevent such information from being used in a manner that may violate this Policy, the law, or your personal privacy. 

#### Plug-ins and Social Media Widgets

ur site may include social media features and widgets, such as the Facebook Like button and the “Share this” button, as well as other interactive mini-programs that run on our site and enable certain features to work (e.g., blogs and comments). These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, or other information, and may set a cookie or use other tracking technology to enable the feature to function properly and for other purposes. These features are displayed on our site, but are hosted by third parties, and are subject to their own privacy policies, not this one.

#### Security

We have implemented safeguards to protect the information we collect from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. Please be aware that despite our best efforts, no data security measures can guarantee 100% security. You should take steps to protect against unauthorized access to your password, phone, and computer by, among other things, signing off after using a shared computer, choosing a robust password that nobody else knows or can easily guess, and keeping your log-in and password private. We are not responsible for any lost, stolen, or compromised passwords or for any activity on your account via unauthorized password activity.

#### Consent to Transfer Personal Information to the United States

If you are located outside of the United States, please note that your Personal Information will be transferred to and processed in the United States. By using our Service, you consent to the transfer and processing of your information in the United States, which may not have the same level of data protection as your home country. You are entirely free not to consent. However, if you do not consent, then we will not be able to provide you with our Service.

#### Access to your Personal Information

Through “My Account” on the Inkling website, you may access, and, in some cases, edit or delete the following information you have provided to us: name and password; email address; billing information; and SNS account association.

The information you can view and update may change as the Service changes. If you have any questions about viewing or updating information we have on file about you, please contact us at support@inkling.com.

#### Children’s privacy

Our Service is not designed for children under 13, and Inkling does not want to collect and does not seek to collect Personal Information from children under 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register with the Service. If we discover that we have collected Personal Information from a child under 13, we will take steps to remove that information from our systems. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at support@inkling.com.

#### Links to Third-Party Websites

We are not responsible for the practices employed by third-party websites linked to or from the Service, nor the information or content contained therein. Please remember that when you use a link to go from the Service to a third-party website, our Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any third-party website, including those that have a link on our website or Service, is subject to that third-party website’s own rules and policies.

#### Updates to this Policy

We may amend this Policy from time to time, so please be sure to check back periodically. Use of information we collect now is subject to the Policy in effect at the time such information is used. If we make any changes to this Policy that materially affect our practices with regard to the Personal Information we have previously collected from you, we will endeavor to notify you in advance of such change by posting an announcement on our Service or contacting you directly via email or other means. You are bound by any changes to the Policy when you use the Service after such changes have been first posted.

#### Contact Us

If you have any questions about our privacy practices or this Policy, please contact us at support@inkling.com.

Last updated: December 1, 2015
